Yael Demers

Physics and Computer Science Major

Bilingual undergraduate student with experience in leadership and self-starting positions. Demonstrating a keen interest in logic, statistics and quantum computing – I seek an internship position in Computer Science to leverage and enrich my understanding of this field.

Montreal, Quebec, Canada

m 🗸

yaeldemers@gmail.com

514. 869. 7736

yaeldemers.github.io

github.com/yaeldemers (

EDUCATION

McGill University

B.Sc. Major Physics and Computer Science 2019-2023

Relevant Coursework:

- Discrete Structure (MATH 240)
- Introduction to Software Systems (COMP 206)
- Introduction to Computer Science (COMP 250)

Collégial International Sainte-Anne

DCS. Pure and Applied Science 2016-2018

WORK EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder and Lead designer

Shark and Sandals, Montreal

2019 - present

- X
- X
- X

Server

Pub la Distillerie, Montreal

2019 - 2020

Data Science Intern

DMD Connecting Healthcare, Chicago

Summer 2018

- Developed a cleansing application to update and optimize databases in Java and Talend
- Lead a software migration to support ETL activities
- Performed a study on the impact of artificial intelligence in healthcare environments

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technologies

C, CSS, HTML 5, Java, Python

Frameworks / Libraries

Bootstrap, Numpy, Pandas, Unix, WordPress

Tools

Adobe Suite, Eclipse, Version Control, Visual Studio Code

SOFT SKILLS

Active Learning

Lateral Thinking

Curiosity

Adaptability

Leadership

Self-Starter

PROJECTS

${\bf Safely-A\ Social\text{-}Based\ Pandemic\ Monitoring\ Application}$

- Designed and co-developed the UI / UX of a mobile application in a 48 hours timeframe using Xaml and C#
- Assisted the integration of the Google Map API and geo-localization into the mobile application

Convolutional Neural Network (CNN)

- · Developed a CNN identifying hand-written digits
- Achieved a digit recognition accuracy of 99.4%

Sudoku Solver Algorithm

 Implemented a backtracking algorithm to solve any single or multiple solutions sudoku puzzle

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Recipient of an honorable mention from the Montreal Police Department (SPVM)
- Awardee of Sainte-Anne's Involvement Scholarship for two consecutive years